# **B KIRAN KUMAR ASHISH**

e-mail id: krnkumar663@gmail.com Contact: +91-9553234145

# **Career Objective**

Al Researcher with 1.5+ year experience in Computer Vision space. Adept at researching and crafting logic-code design which can right away put into production. Instrumental in integrating various domains to build an end-to-end platform.

# **Professional Experience**

# 2019-06- Computer Vision Engineer

### till date Viume

Currently designing and developing Computer Vision algorithms and techniques for Fashion attributes and household attributes.

### 2019-04- Al Team Lead & Al Researcher

## **2019-06 Hexvel Disruptor**, *Hyderabad*.

➤ Designed and Developed Deep Learning techniques for cricket assessment for impeding a learning curve with integration of IoT Bat sensor.

### 2019-02- Al Engineer

## **2019-03** Tericsoft Technology, Hyderabad.

- Performed various Deep Learning techniques on Image Classification, Detection, and Segmentation on numerous real-time use-cases with realtime visual data.
- ➤ Intensively worked on Edge-devices such as Jetson Nano, Raspy by performing computer vision operations on them, with an aim to increasing FPS on live streaming.
- ➤ Delivered Deep Learning projects with different architecture-cycles such as Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras, OpenCV.
- Managed all necessary installations required for GPU enabling during model-training phase such as CUDA, NVCC, CuDNN and so forth.
- Hacked bug-fixing and error-solving IN and OUT.
- Acted as Operational Lead Generation for 2 months by giving product pitching to the Investors and key-players.

### **Summary**

Overall experience in Tericsoft is my self-growth and learning curve. I dealt with several real-time visual-data projects that are to be delivered in a short span. The pressure handling and short span delivery is what I nurtured. The motto for this is "Jugaad" way. Now, my foremost research here is building and developing self-custom neural network architecture for

classification and detection. Every project I get and before I start, I draw a mindmap and then proceed.

# **Research Experience**

## 2018- Computer Vision Research

#### till date

Started off my research journey in the Computer Vision when I was in my 3<sup>rd</sup> grade of Bachelors. Kickstarted with MATLAB tool, I participated in many competitions and worn many hats in learning from failures during my Bachelors' days. Step by Step, my passion and hunger for computer vision has grown and now with enough experience I can take up any challenge that comes in the upfront and solve it. Started with Plant Disease Detection to custom YOLO Detection, now dealing with custom-building architectures, I have learnt many things and correcting my mistakes during my learning curve in error solving, bug fixing, problem-solving methodology, the insights I got and grasped are immeasurable. Yet, I'm a lifelong learner in Computer Vision realm and hungry to achieve and contribute many gears.

### 2018- Research Student

# till date Under the esteem guidance of Dr.Farukh Hashmi, NIT Warangal.

I started my research career in Computer Vision with my Professor Dr. Farukh Hashmi sir, who is now working as Assistant Professor at NIT Warangal campus. We alongside with few other people deal with research in latest innovations in the Computer Vision field and are meant to contribute by publishing in premier conferences such as CVPR, ICML, ECCV, ICCV, NIPS and so forth.

### **Publications**

# GAIT analysis: 3D Pose Estimation and Prediction in Defence Applications using Pattern Recognition

International Conference of Machine Vision held at Amsterdam, 2019 (https://www.spiedigitallibrary.org/conference-proceedings-of-spie/11433/2559368/GAIT-analysis--3D-pose-estimation-and-prediction-in-defence/10.1117/12.2559368.short?SSO=1)

Subjective and Objective assessment for variation of plant nitrogen contents to air pollutants using machine intelligence

A book chapter in the book titled Fuzzy Expert Systems and Applications in Agricultural Diagnosis (<a href="https://www.igi-global.com/gateway/chapter/233217">https://www.igi-global.com/gateway/chapter/233217</a>)

FashionFit: Analysis of Mapping 3D Pose and Neural Body Fit for Custom Virtual Try-on *IEEE Open Access* (<a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9091008/">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9091008/</a>)

# An Exploratory Analysis on Visual Counterfeits Using Conv-LSTM Hybrid Architecture

IEEE Open Access (https://doi.org/10.1109/access.2020.2998330)

Reviewed 3 papers given for IEEE Access publication.

Publons Profile: <a href="https://publons.com/researcher/3527972/b-kiran-kumar-ashish/">https://publons.com/researcher/3527972/b-kiran-kumar-ashish/</a>

ORCiD Profile: https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6582-4009

### **Demonstrated Achievements**

## **Certificate of Merit** (*Professional-Level*)

Represented my company as one of the top 10 finalists out of overall 200 teams all over India as a part of Boeing & T-Hub BUILD competition. Received Certificate of Merit from *Jayesh Ranjan* (Principal Secretary of IT & IC, Government of Telangana) and *Ravi Narayan* (CEO, T-Hub).

# **Hackathons** (College-Level)

- Mentored to the winning team in the Smart India Hackathon-2020, Software Edition for problem statement issued by VMWare India on Electric Vehicle theme.
- > Smart India Hackathon: 2-time finalists for the software edition and lead the team.
- ➤ Winner of Smart City Hackathon held at IIT, Hyderabad.

### **Education**

Electronics and Communication Engineering

2015-2019

Anurag Group of Institutions, Hyderabad

**CGPA: 8.77** 

Executive Certification on Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning 2020

IIIT-Hyderabad and Talent Sprint Grade: Excellent

# Internship

2018-11- Computer Vision Intern

**2019-01** Algoleap Technologies, CIE, IIIT-H, Hyderabad

Dealt with experimenting Neural Networks in Bio-medical imaging, particularly focussing on Diabetic Retinopathy.

### **Skills**

# **Development Skills**

# **Python**

Basic-Advance operations needed in Pre-Processing operations.

Managed automating preprocessing techniques.

# > Deep Learning

Executed numerous applications in different domains using Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch, YOLO, K-NN, Mask R-CNN, Faster RCNN frameworks using real-time visual data in real-time production level.

Edge-Computing: Running OpenCV, Deep Learning operations such as facial recognition, live streaming using MTCNN and MXNET framework.

### GitHub Profile: https://github.com/ashish-AIML

### **Presentation Skills**

Technical Content Writer, Investor and Product Presentation, Business Communication.

## **Language Skills**

English, Telugu, Hindi.

## **Interests/Hobbies**

- Knowing about new technology and sharing with others.
- Watching TEDx talks, Famous Personalities Speeches, and Spiritual Videos.
- Reading autobiographies and novels.

### **Personal Details**

Fathers' name: Late B. Subrahmanyam

Date of Birth: 12<sup>th</sup>-July-1997.

Address: 16-11-16/1/1/1, Saleem Nagar Colony, Malakpet, Hyderabad-500036.

Date: 28/08/2020.

**B Kiran Kumar Ashish**